of the ceasefire. They never stopped bombing
South Lebanon. Um since then, until February 28th,
they had killed through their um attacks and their
their uh bombings hundreds of Lebanese civilians.
They never stopped um also uh using what do you
say? White phosphorus, which Amnesty International
uh deems it's it's I mean it's not a legal
means of war. It causes long-term injuries,
severe burns, and destruction of farmland.
We know why they're doing that since people
are not deserting South Lebanon. They want to
destroy their livelihoods so that they do end
up deserting South Lebanon. And the latest is that
Israel has issued what do you say a directive that
53 villages and ts of South Lebanon needed
to be evacuated. And the sad uh truth of the
matter is as we speak 300,000 Lebanese from South
Lebanon have acted up on those orders descending
upon Beirut and other parts of Lebanon living
in tents or in their cars or with family. So
uh and they've killed since March 1st um hundreds
of civilians, 85 of them being um children. How
realistic is the greater Israel project today as
we speak? I reg as as far as Lebanon is concerned.
Yeah, I think that the Israelis have guaranteed
that Lebanon will be a failed state. I don't
think any Israeli government is going to
allow Lebanon to flourish as a nation.
Um, I think we will continue to see Israeli
attacks, Israeli forced displacement of
civilians. I read a statistic yesterday that
by the end of the week, as many as 700,000
Lebanese will be internally displaced. This is a
humanitarian disaster and and the world, most of
the world isn't focused on it because they're
all watching what's unfolding in Iran. Well,
Lebanon already doesn't have enough food, enough
medical uh care, enough clean water. Uh it's
it's only going to get worse. So, take that and
couple it with these these incredibly provocative
statements made by the by the fascist evangelical
American ambassador to Israel, Mike Huckabe,
uh to Tucker Carlson two weeks ago that he has
no problem with greater Israel and said, quote,
"They should just take it." And what what he meant
by it was all Arab land from the Euphrates River
to the Nile. Just take it. He doesn't care. So if
that's the attitude of the of the representative
of the president of the United States, then
I think we should all be living in fear. Um I
wanted to um ask you before we close this, how do
you see this ending? I mean, not the war as such,
but all this like um thing we're living under, you
know, greater Israel and all this shred of greater
Israel and it's becoming more and more realistic.
And up until a few years ago, it was just like,
"Oh, you're a conspiracy theorist for um even
mentioning it, but it's all out in the open
now. They're making public statements about it."
Um, uh, Netanyahu has, uh, been caught on camera
publicly stating that it's his lifelong ambition.
When the war started, he he he was happy to speak
on camera and saying, "This has been 40 years in
the making for me, a dream for me, the war with
Iran, because Iran is their last um um, what do
you say? Um, thing stopping them from realizing
the greater Israel project." Well, Iran and
Turkey, which is why Nafali Bennett, the former
Israeli prime minister, is also now saying after
Iran, it's Turkey. Turkeykey's next. So, what do
you how do you see all this ending? I mean, do you
see them realizing these goals because they they
weren't so close to realizing them a few years
ago, but now it's it's all, you know, unraveling.
I don't see them succeeding. There are too
many Arabs. There are too many Muslims. There
are too many people who oppose this this naked
Israeli aggression. Um, I don't even care. Well,
I shouldn't say I don't care because I care very
much, but I don't think it matters even if the
United States were to support such a crazy
position. And and the United States wouldn't
support such a crazy position. Um Mike Huckabe is
is a fluke in the system, but they have he'll be
gone soon, John. They have I mean they're they're
not not a not a greater Israel. The the But what
are all these wars that the US have been doing
has been doing over the last 25 years, the seven
nations that um BB kept saying that they need to
get out out of the way to topple their regimes,
they they've reached the seventh nations. So
who has done those wars on their behalf? But
it's America who started wars on their behalf.
Look at them independently though. Libya was
no threat to Israel. Never. Never was, never
would be. Libya was was a thorn in the side of
the United States. The the US didn't overthrow and
kill Gaddafi for Israel. We did it for ourselves.
Same in Somalia. Somalia is no threat to Israel
at all. Never was. Um they were a threat to the
United States or to at least to American commerce,
excuse me. Um, Afghanistan, I mean, that was for a
while that was a righteous war. It was a war uh to
destroy al-Qaeda. It morphed into something that
was wrong. It morphed into this never- ending
war against the Taliban, who had never attacked
the United States. But in the beginning,
that was a righteous war. We had to destroy
al-Qaeda. It's not that the Israelis wanted us
to. Um, it certainly was in Israel's interest,
but that was the United States all the way. You
know, listen, I I am not a fan of Israel. I am
even less of a fan of Israeli leadership, but we
can't blame all of our problems on Israel. We can
blame the United States for its for its mistakes,
too. Well, on Libya, I I I beg to defer because it
was Gaddafi and him making the announcement that,
you know, he's going to um unhook the um petrol
uh uh Yeah. That's what I'm saying. From That's
what I'm saying. That was a that was a threat
to the American economy. We didn't need the
Israelis to egg us on to overthrow Gaddafi.
Well, I mean, the Israelis were also uh um
purporting that he was funding so-called Arab
terrorists and stuff. So, and and yeah,
BB has been on record naming the seven.
They they've had a strong a strong grip on your
politicians for sure for the last 30 years, John.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Of course. No, I I'm not denying
that American and Israeli interests intersect. I'm
just saying that that these seven countries on the
list, while some of them absolutely are enemies of
of Israel, um the US had in their own national
interests reasons to overthrow them. Understood.
Okay. Now, my last question, a very concerning
one. The Samson option. I mean, I'm sure everyone
thinks it's not going to happen. It's very
far-fetched, but um with them in power now, BB
and everyone, I mean, you can’t tell. So, I mean,
do how how plausible do you think they would were
they would use it if Israel believed that it was
close to losing this very important war for itself
or losing support from America on this war? Uh,
would they resort to that the new use of nuclear
weapons as a last resort? If the Israelis believed
that the state of Israel was untenable because of,
you know, Arab advances, for example, that there
were Arab or Iranian threats that could lead
eventually even to the end of the state of Israel.
Yes, I think they would use the Samson option. You
know, I I gave an interview yesterday in which I
said that even a year ago, I would have said that
was ridiculous. It was it was it was a a doom
uh ideology. And now I I have to say that yeah,
I I believe the Israelis would would carry this
out if they really believed they were in threat
of collapse. Yes, they would take everybody
out with them. And analysts say, even though
the Israelis have never have never acknowledged
the existence of a uh of a nuclear uh program
or nuclear arsenal, analysts tell us that they
have between 80 and 200 warheads. That's enough
to kill everybody. Everybody. Yeah. Very scary. Uh
one last question. Your thoughts on the um rapid
accumulation of all this this military buildup
in Cyprus. You have Spain, you know of them. Um,
Spain has uh deployed um a frigate (ESPS Cristóbal
Colón) and Italy has deployed um the another air
defense frigate (FREMM-class air-defence frigate).
France has deployed the um aircraft carrier,
Charles de Gaulle with frigate Languedoc and
advanced anti-missile anti- drone systems to
Cyprus. Greece has deployed um two frigates Kimon
& Psaras. Kimon is considered amongst the most
technologically advanced frigates currently in
operational service worldwide. Four F-16 fighter
jets and a Hellenic Air Force C-130 transport
aircraft. The United Kingdom is sending over HMS
Dragon. This is like uh where is it today? Nine
days after the attack, the drone attacked their
bases. They’re still going to send the HMS Dragon.
They have serious problems with their military. I
mean the finances with their military is down
the hole. The Netherlands also has sent over a
frigate (HNLMS Evertsen) and over the last over
a matter of um just six days this small island
in the corner of the Mediterranean Sea has seen
the most high-level visits we've ever seen in a
matter of I don’t know we haven't seen them maybe
ever in even in the span of a year. We've had the
Greek defense minister visits Cyprus March 3rd
with the top brass of the Greek army to coordinate
defense planning with the Cypriote counterparts.
March 5th, the UK defense minister visits Cyprus
to meet with his Cypriot counterpart. Uh March
6th, Friday, the president of the president of
the Republic of Cyprus met with MI6 Chief Blaise
Metreweli at the presidential palace. And on
Monday, March 9th, Emanuel Macron and Greek Prime
Minister Kyriakos Mitsotakis visited Cyprus for
consultations. just your word on what's happening
and why. As bad a policy as this is, the NATO
militaries and even more broadly the European
Union militaries feel compelled to at least
have the appearance of being supportive of Israel
and the United States. And so behind closed doors